I realize and I have this you need to
like perfect an idea before I share it
or start talking after the video starts
that I have a need to perfect an idea
before sharing it instead of sharing it
like well it's ruminating and then it
never perfects itself really so less
ideas get shared and that is also from
ego and gets to go away and anyway had
the urge took a bit figuring out this
difference between competition and
cooperation it's not the first time and
the difference between like voluntary
competition certain voluntary
cooperation versus forced cooperation
it's a lot of a stuff up and doing is
dealing with like in my head like
communism versus capitalism and but like
don't like this negative side of
communism don't worry we can have just
the positive and just the positive
capitalism those are very like defined
things and they've both been tried many
times like in history and um yeah so
voluntary forced like con isms forced
cooperation it's enforced for my that's
like a central dictatorship I'm a
dictator to us burn up after them and I
mean the ideas are supposed to give it
back to you like once they've taught you
how to be a nice loving human then we'll
give it back to you and well you're not
being treated like a nice loving human
like the thing like this group isn't
necessarily great at that they're just
like but if we have this anyway forced
voluntary cooperation competition so
voluntary competition is like sports and
this somewhat good side of capitalism
like hey I made these rugs and like I'd
really like to like competing with other
people in the work here but like
everyone benefits but that doesn't
really exist so I don't
just like rocks you mean the slave labor
making yet no okay so first cooperation
is all about and I was thinking about
more mistakes in general that in
competition with within capitalism with
mistakes and when it's voluntary then
it's not voluntary but like you
voluntarily go into the business
no be nut I'm busy tell her right before
I come on no I am busy nope what I'm not
opening that I'll be back okay this is
life yes
after I'm done doing what I'm doing
which I told you not to interrupt I will
be out to help you with your thing how
about those girls and yep you'll have to
figure out patience or emotions that
there is cooperation voluntary forced
the capital isn't like when you fail
your business fails right and there's a
lot of this like jumping on weakness in
caught I don't know if it's because
we're all in competition I think it's
because we're all in competition with
each other and we see weakness in
someone else and it triggers the
weakness in us and we we pounce
repeatedly like lots of people and also
just like a lot of like regret like it
happens law voluntary competition so
competition forced competition first
competition is the downside conveys like
that it like because it's forced and
it's not this team trying to be its best
and this team trying to be its best and
then competing against each other and
then like good game good game like in a
real authentic way like yeah that's
we lost but we're gonna try and get
better it's like a like I don't know
like it's a more like you are looser
because you fail the business because
you didn't get the good grades because
you didn't it's a very focuses on
strengths and weaknesses and one side is
better in one side is worse and
cooperation because you need to work
together it's not tug-of-war it's like
how do we make this rope into a nice I
don't know something you make ropes into
she thought about that analogy before
saying it and once it's yeah like
capitalism businesses fail and so people
try something and risk it and and a lot
of us don't even do that because it's
scary to fail at something and to be
seen as internally or externally is a
failure so they don't take the risk and
when they do take the risk and they the
business fails and they you know feel
like failure anyway and a lot of the
businesses fail in forced cooperation I
hate you communism thinking of first
because there's this purse like some
people don't want to cooperate and
different people don't want to cooperate
in different ways like just I'm a
cooperator if someone else was telling
me how I had to cooperate I would be
less of a operator her
I want to cooperate all the time unless
you like demands that I do it and said
I'm not going to that's not gonna feel
right to me but voluntary cooperation
means that people can like some degree
your speed not to sunder you are just
we're starting with the ground level of
cooperation of people who are
co-operators that was like that's all we
need that's all we need but that's not
really true because there's this other
piece of the soil that is we're allowed
to make mistakes and we're allowed to be
wrong like it's individual on top off
days like there's values we hold but
you're not punished when you don't meet
though because it
not one mandatory to meet most of them
and to she's like having a punitive
society is it happy like voluntary
cooperation is where it's at but because
the other thing like because we're in a
society that's forced competition we get
the added benefit of like that's already
existing and we get to compete with it
and see if we can do better than that
that like essentially there's like okay
we've already decided forced competition
this is sports competition but it's also
voluntary competition we're like bawling
we're like yes we can actually make a
better product together and then you can
make by yourself any and all of you and
a piece of that is the brand team the
size young value the entity yeah but I
can't I think it was word quality a good
thing that attaches to something okay
now I forgot what I was saying not that
I didn't even figure out for it anyway
but creating a society not even a
society because we're creating a society
but we're starting with a corporate
entity which seems so counterintuitive
but the legal structure and what it is
in capitalism gives us so much power
together gives us many opportunities
that we don't have without that
corporate structure you can call it
anything you want it's gonna have a
legal corporate structure just like you
know get married or just call yourselves
married not have a piece paper it's like
okay we could just call us so it's a
different thing we still probably need
the piece paper showing more
incorporation if we want all the legal
safety that's everything but being a
cooperative and actual thing except that
cooperatives aren't global.nomads has
global members so I think we're there is
there is a precedent and we can have a
PC co-op that is global members but
whether that's the best for our tax
strategy and everything else is a whole
other it's a whole other entity and
need to figure that out together as a
board once there's a board voluntary but
starting with people who are this is
where I'm like oh yeah this is why you
were supposed to show the other piece
because the more I'm on my authentic
self the more it's gonna bring in other
people who are authentic and the more on
allowed to make mistakes the more other
people are allowed to make mistakes and
what we want is a culture of instead of
when so makes this mistake we jump on
them for weakness or they have to like
just defend what they've done and
therefore dig deeper and deeper okay
like moment actually what you just said
like I felt like you're reacting to me
in that way because I'm black or white
but let's say I don't know something
stuff it's like okay well I don't think
I was acting like that people are
allowed to make mistakes because we all
make mistakes and people are where they
are and I don't we're just so
unforgiving in our society right now and
if that was helping the the the word is
like the non privileged class
in all of the groups the unprivileged
ones I might be okay with it like I'd
have to reexamine but it doesn't it
doesn't help them in all yelling at
people about racism isn't stopping
racism yelling at people to just stop
being homophobic isn't making their
hearts open what has made their hearts
open and made culture shift from Ellen
coming out and being ostracized and all
of the celebrities coming out is like
yeah bisexual and pansexual and I'm gay
and it's like just a difference they're
still courage there but it's not the
same as Ellen when she when she did it
and I'm dating sidetrack now cuz I had
that thought earlier no just go back to
that um
like when you're ostracized and Ellen
like Ellen's Ellen because of what she
did because society kind of turned her
back on her and our Hollywood and
overall society anyway that doesn't good
like love and like Ellen doing that
helped us fall more in love especially
now that she's on TV like there's tons
of people who are like oh well as long
as you're not too gay I'll watch you and
like and which opens the doorway to
acceptance and like I don't need you to
accept me but I need society to accept
me I feel like that's a bigger deal in
order for that to happen we have to
allow people to open not to yell at them
because it's like okay well Society
wasn't that way two decades ago so we
can't expect people that are like back
in the Mintel hoodie from two decades
ago to just like ketchup test you when
all of society's yelling at them for and
they're building up stronger and
stronger barriers we have to come from a
place of love and I don't know exactly
what that looks like
I know it looks like we keep people safe
but truly safe not you get zero triggers
ever because you we can't do that with
everybody's triggers triggers teach us
things and it's ridiculous like either
no one's allowed to cause a negative
emotion on someone or it's not illegal
to cause a negative emotion on someone I
can't so I can't really be that doesn't
mean that Everett like people can't have
this movie would walk around all day
just throwing hate speech at each other
because that's a ridiculous thing
whether it's based on the actual like
hate speech of a group or just like
yelling at people for their what we do
online like that's not helping anyone
might be helping the person get a little
bit of their anger out and frustrated
it's not moving them forward it's not
getting them to open up it's not getting
them so no more important to us but
starting with voluntary co-operators
means we can start from a place of
people who want to be part of that which
are going to be people who want to work
in community they're gonna hopefully be
people who are like overly overall less
races but unless we can own that we're
all racist that we're all homophobic
that we're all misogynistic cuz we live
in that society and we're all have to
deal with that in different levels based
on who we actually are until we can own
that and like be like okay this is
really weird to yell at people to stop
having their brain work a certain way
I'd like just stop being racist stop
having those thoughts like it's like
okay but how how do you have it because
I don't have a solution I've never been
racist like that I've had racist like um
subconscious stuff that I'm like I
didn't even think about that like I
didn't think that was racist and it's I
can't think of an instance where
somebody else pointed something out to
me besides like language and stuff which
is not my strong suit
and also it's more about not wine or her
people rather than coming to it on my
own of like oh yeah I can see not the
language they make sense there's certain
words I'm like oh how could you say that
the whole time that's very hurtful and I
can see other words I'm like I don't see
how that's that hurtful I think it's
more hurtful do you think that's hurtful
and then it's actually hurtful I'm
talking specifically about ableist
language forced voluntary or involuntary
cooperation and competition always kid
right away
voluntary forced help yeah those are
just some of my thoughts you're working
it out I'll be back after do you think
about more things probably not in camera
probably do this one tonight no one ever
comes out and I love it that like I can
feel the internal shift happening I'm
like watching the Twitter numbers go up
right now causes me joy even though it's
like three a day oh my god three extra
followers like I'm like but it feels
authentically happy like I'm like these
are people are gonna help me I don't
know what these people these people
Robert not the people that are gonna
help me they're just more like I have to
it's like the ridiculousness of it and
I'm having fun with it like it's like
you have to go out and be on social
media and like get a following in order
to put an idea out there when the idea
is good is ridiculous so we need to
calculate and put solutions in the world
and once I've done this other people
aren't gonna have to if they want to do
it the old stream way they may have to
but like there will be a way to do it
links and things that are like that
exist that are capitalistic that are
like oh come on the Sharks tank will
give you money and help eat it up we're
gonna take a big chunk of your company
that doesn't work because it's um this
needs to be owned by everyone I thought
a cordon truck tank he liked or here
would be Dragons Den I'm being like it's
like yes for 1 million dollars I will
give you one out of seven and a half
billion shares that's the valuation for
one ohto 7.5 billion mm-hmm not because
cuz you're humans you can't ever have
more than like one human entities sure
million of dollars to be great and then
also not really just like if I had
health right away I wouldn't be Who I am
and I wouldn't be learning whatever
lessons are gonna come down the pipeline
with my health but I would still choose
it so like thank God that is an exact
same thing like getting this money in
the way that I envision getting the
money is exactly how we move it forward
and so yes if somebody drops a million
dollars my lap I'm gonna use it I'm
gonna figure it out I'm gonna make make
stuff happen but doing it in this way is
the it's the path and that's part of it
part of it is it like if something just
to happen to stumble upon this was like
hey even though we I don't understand
what you're doing here is a million
dollars I would take it
transparently slug this transparent and
then we could I would then I could be
like I have a million dollars which
would be much more fun video today Ivan
those dollars come help me figure out
how to spend it and it wouldn't be quite
the democracy like I wouldn't want to do
it that way I think before I whatever
one been like any 10,000 people I don't
like no they
need to put money in the game like if
they haven't put money in the game then
it's not or something the game otherwise
you get the trolls and the other side to
culture of like jumping on everyone cuz
it's because they've done one thing
wrong and we need to find a way to
discuss what like actually happened and
both sides and like both sides can
actually be right there doesn't need to
be like oh your way is right it's like
oh your feelings were hurt and you
didn't mean to hurt that hurt the
feelings like yes those are both things
and could be maybe not feelings the
future if it's a thing to not redo but
also I heard people's feelings on repeat
when I know better I do better but like
I still I mean I don't know hurts
people's feelings on a trip them but it
annoys them for sure and I do it like oh
yeah hit that again he did that again
and I can't not like it's fine every
time we'll go back to be like nope don't
do it don't do it and it was still
happen thank god it's that I know
reasons oh thank god
but we have to we have to have
compassion for each other this week
anger and hatred is winning out because
we're allowing it to win out like it's
like have to go I'm getting off by
twenties less than a minute but like on
Twitter I'm now on Twitter I wasn't on
Twitter before when I would say this but
like it's like Twitter yelled at this
person Twitter a great road right and
it's like no like 10 people said
something mean and 100 people said
something good like unless you're
actually gonna compare the two
just cuz someone said something horrible
yeah it's the intra someone's always
gonna say something horrible but it's
like how you blow said horrible versus
said nice versus said neutral no it's a
neutral stuff but like we let hatred
went out we let like the anger speak
louder and the Australasian like no
matter what you do anything you do as a
parent anything someone's coracle stuff
the people are gonna be like okay yeah
but my kid in Vegas trips for dinner
it's what happens
um we just need to do better
kidneys past 20 so I'm gonna go an alpha
real these are getting too long stay in
too long